nhra.com 2018-03-06

# Privacy Policy | NHRA

Last Updated:  January 18, 2017

The National Hot Rod Association ("NHRA" or “we”, “our”, or “us”) knows that safeguarding your privacy is important.  This policy (“Privacy Policy”) describes the kinds of information we gather from you, how this information is used and protected, and how you can control its use.  **This Privacy Policy covers the privacy practices of NHRA with respect to information collected through both:   (1) our “Online Services” which includes our web sites (each a “Website”) and any applications published or operated by NHRA to access our content or services through your mobile, tablet computer or other similar device (each a “Mobile App”), however accessed and used, whether via personal computers, mobile devices or otherwise, and also any widgets, applications, interactive features and/or downloads that are owned or operated by NHRA and available through these Websites or Mobile Apps or that post a link to this Privacy Policy; and (2) our “offline” activities – such as collection of data by telephone, in-person (such as at NHRA events), by mail, paper documents or other such offline means operated, provided or made available by NHRA.  **

**By accessing or using our Websites or downloading, installing or using any Mobile App, or otherwise giving us your information, you accept the terms of this Privacy Policy and expressly consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information according to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to our policies and practices, do not access our Websites, or download, install or use our Mobile Apps, or give us any of your information.   **

As we update and expand our Online Services, this Privacy Policy may change.  So please review it from time to time. 

**1.               What is Personal Information?**

"Personal Information" is information that identifies a person or allows a person to be located. Examples of personal information include a name, a home address, an e-mail address, a telephone number, or a Social Security number.

We may also collect demographic information about you, such as gender, age range, occupation, or other such category information that does not identify or locate you personally (“Demographic Information”).  We do not consider Demographic Information about you to be Personal Information unless it is associated with Personal Information so as to permit identification of you.  If we combine Demographic Information with the Personal Information we collect, we will treat it as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

**2.               When Do We Collect Personal Information and What Kind of Information is Collected?** 

**(a)   Information You Provide To Us.** 

We collect Personal Information you provide us through various means.  If you request additional information about NHRA, register to become an NHRA member, make a purchase on or through NHRA.com or an affiliated Website such as NHRAStore.com or NationalDragster.net, download and install a Mobile App or participate in other services NHRA may offer on its Online Services, we may request information (such as your name, mailing address, telephone number, e-mail address, fax number, Social Security number, driver’s license number or other government issued ID number, birth date and credit card information) in order to respond to your inquiries and requests. If you make a purchase in any online NHRA store, NHRA will collect shipping and financial information. Certain activities, such as registering to become a member, racer registration, other racer functions or racer matters, or installing a Mobile App, may require that you select a username and password. From time to time, we may request information from you regarding your membership or race activities, or generally via surveys, sweepstakes, contests, or other means. Participation in online racer registration and other functions or matters, and in surveys, sweepstakes, contests or similar matters, is voluntary; you have a choice whether or not to disclose this information.  

                  **(b) Information We Collect Via Technology**

In addition to any Personal Information or other information that you choose to submit to us, we and our third-party service providers may use a variety of now and later developed methods or technologies that automatically or passively collect certain information whenever you visit or interact with the Online Services (“Usage Information”).  This Usage Information may include the browser you are using, the URL that referred you to our Online Services, all of the areas within our Online Services that you visit, and the time of day, among other information.  We may use Usage Information for a variety of purposes, including to enhance or otherwise improve the Online Services and your interaction with them.  In addition, we collect your IP address or other unique identifier (“Device Identifier”) for your computer or other devices used to access the Online Services (any, a “Device”).  A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your Device used to access the Services, and our computers identify your Device by its Device Identifier. 

A few of the methods and technologies that may be used to collect Usage Information include the following:

**_Cookies_**.  A cookie is a data file placed on a Device when it is used to access the Online Services.  A Flash cookie is a data file placed on a Device via the Adobe Flash plugin that may be built-in to or downloaded by you to your Device. Cookies and Flash cookies are standard in the industry; you’ll find them at most major websites.  Cookies and Flash cookies may be used for many purposes, including, without limitation, remembering you and your preferences and tracking your visits to our web pages.  If you choose to disable cookies or Flash cookies on your Device, some features of the Online Services may not function properly.

**_IP Address._**   An IP address is a number that's automatically assigned to your computing Device whenever you’re surfing the web - your computing Device’s unique "signature."  Web servers automatically identify your computing Device by its IP address. When you visit our Online Services, we collect some general information about your computing Device, including its IP address, the operating system it uses (for example, Windows XP), the browser software it uses (for example, Microsoft Internet Explorer), and your Internet service provider (for example, AT&T). This information helps us better understand the people who visit our Online Services.  We collect this general information to identify the most popular areas on our Online Services and to provide aggregate information to our advertisers to let them know about the number of people who have seen and clicked on.

**_Web Beacons._**   Small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons (also known as “1x1 GIFs” or “clear GIFs”) may be included in our web and mobile pages and email messages.  Web beacons may be invisible to you, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into a web page or email can act as a web beacon.  Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to the Online Services, to monitor how users navigate the Online Services, to count how many emails that were sent were actually opened or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed.

**_Embedded Scripts._**   An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the Online Services, such as the links you click on.  The code is temporarily downloaded onto your Device from our web server or a third party service provider, is active only while you are connected to the Online Services, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

**(c)   Information From Other Sources**

We may from time to time supplement the information we collect about you with information from other sources, including but not limited to, third-party verification services, credit bureaus, mailing list providers, and publicly available sources.  This may be done for various purposes, such as to obtain information validating your address or information you provided to us, including, without limitation, in order to enhance our ability to serve you, to tailor our content to you and to offer you opportunities to purchase products or services that we believe may be of interest to you.  Thus, information we obtain may be intermingled with and used in conjunction with information obtained through other sources, including both offline and online sources.  In those cases, we will apply this Privacy Policy to any Personal Information received, unless we have stated otherwise.

You may also choose to participate in a third party application (such as one of our Facebook applications or a similar application on a third party web site) through which you allow us to collect (or the third party to share) information about you, including Personal Information.  The third party may allow you to remove the application, in which case we will no longer collect information about you through the application, but we may retain the information previously collected.  In addition, we may receive information about you if other users of a third party web site give us access to their profiles and you are one of their “friends” or information about you is otherwise accessible through your friend’s web page, profile page, or similar page on a social networking or other third party web site or interactive service.

**(d) Information You Provide About A Third Party**

If you send someone else a communication from or through our Online Services, such as sending an article to a friend or information about our events or products, we use the information you provide (typically, names and email addresses) to facilitate the communication and we do not use it for any other marketing purpose, unless we obtain consent from that person.

**(e)   Information Collected by Mobile Apps **

For our Mobile Apps, you agree that we may collect and use technical data and related information, including but not limited to, technical information about your Device, system and application software, and peripherals, that is gathered periodically to facilitate the provision of software updates, product support and other services to you (if any) related to any Mobile Apps.

If we implement one or more Mobile Apps, the Mobile App may automatically collect and store some or all of the following information from your mobile Device (“Mobile Device Information”), including without limitation:

  * Your preferred language and country site (if applicable)
  * Your phone number or other unique Device identifier assigned to your mobile Device
  * The mobile Device manufacturer and model of your mobile Device
  * The IP address of your mobile device
  * Your mobile operating system
  * The type of mobile Internet browsers you are using
  * Information about how you interact with the Mobile App and any of our Website to which the Mobile App links, such as how many times you use a specific part of the Mobile App over a given time period, the amount of time you spend using the Mobile App, how often you use the Mobile App, actions you take in the Mobile App and how you engage with the Mobile App
  * Information to allow us to personalize the services and content available through the Mobile App
  * Your geolocation

We may use information automatically collected by Mobile Apps (including the Mobile Device Information) in the following ways:

  * To operate and improve our Mobile Apps, other Online Services, our company's services, and tools;
  * To create aggregated and anonymized information to determine which Mobile App features are most popular and useful to users, and for other statistical analyses;
  * To prevent, discover and investigate violations of this Privacy Policy or any applicable terms of use, terms of service, or end user license agreement for the Mobile App;
  * To customize the content or services on the Mobile App for you, or the communications sent to you through the App Application (if any)

We may associate your unique Device Identifier or Mobile App usage information with any Personal Information you provide. 

For purposes of your use of any of our Mobile Apps and the services offered through any Mobile App, the Mobile App may also collect certain information about you (including Personal Information) that you knowingly supply to the Mobile App such as the following:

  * Your user name and any password required by the Mobile App
  * Age
  * Gender
  * Mailing or other address
  * Zip code
  * Telephone number
  * Email address
  * Photos uploaded by you

Registration may be required and Personal Information may also be collected if there is content from the Mobile App that you specifically and knowingly upload to an online community, website or to the public, e.g. uploaded photos, posted reviews. This uploaded content will also be subject to the privacy policy of the platform to which you upload the content.

**3.               How Do We Use the Personal Information We Collect?**

(a)  We gather, store and archive the information about you we collect from our Online Services and offline activities. We may use the Personal Information we collect about you for various purposes including to : (i) provide products, information, or services, or to process transactions that you have requested or agreed to receive, such as racer registration, other racer services, membership and subscription services, fulfill a purchase for merchandise or tickets, or to send you electronic newsletters or other publications; (ii) sell and promote NHRA events, tickets and merchandise, and processing transactions for them, (iii) operate, maintain and improve our Online Services; (iv) conduct marketing and research analysis, and product service and development; (v) advertise, market and promote products and services we feel may be of interest to you; (vi) process entries for sweepstakes, contests or other promotions, and deliver rewards or prizes; (vii) engage in record-keeping; (vii) respond to comments and questions from users; (ix) improve the Online Services and to customize your experience on the Online Services to individual visitors, or to serve you specific content that is most relevant to you; (x) enable you to participate in a variety of the Online Services’ features, such as message boards and other features, online entry and registration forms, user-generated content functions, and interactive features; (xi) process your registration with the Online Services, including verifying your email address is active and valid; (xii) to contact you with regard to your use of our Online Services or offline activities, or tickets, events, products, promotions, surveys, or new developments or events, and in our discretion, changes to the Online Services and/or the Online Services’ policies; (xiii) perform internal business purposes; (xiv) develop an individual profile or a profile of certain groups of visitors to or users of our Online Services or ; (xv) for purposes disclosed at the time you provide your information or as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy.

If you do not want to be contacted about our new, products, events, and promotions, you can let us know at any time. See section 6 below "How Can You Review, Edit or Delete Personal Information?  However, opting out of receiving information electronically from NHRA may reduce your level of service from NHRA

(b) Further, we may use third party analytics and other service providers to evaluate and provide us with information about the use of the Online Services and viewing of our content.  These third parties may set and access their own tracking technologies and methods such as cookies, web beacons and embedded scripts on your Device and they may otherwise collect or have access to information about you, including Usage Information.   When using the Online Services, certain third parties may collect Personal Information about your online activities over time and across different websites.  This Privacy Policy does not govern such third party tracking technologies but does govern our collection and use of your Usage Information we receive in connection therewith.

(c)  Please note that when you submit information to the Online Services via a “contact us” or other similar function, you may not always receive a response.  You may choose not to provide NHRA with any contact information; however, in that case, we will be unable to respond to your request for NHRA information, process your order for products, tickets or other services, sign you up for NHRA membership or race registration, or allow you to participate in other Online Services that require personal information.  Additionally, your ability to navigate our Online Services may be limited.  

**4.               How And When We Disclose Personal Information About You to Third Parties?**

NHRA may share Usage Information and Demographic Information with third parties for their use.  In addition, NHRA may share Personal Information we have collected about you  as disclosed at the time you provide your information and as described below or otherwise in this Privacy Policy. 

**_(a) For Third-Party Marketing Purposes.   _**NHRA may disclose your Personal Information to advertisers, marketers, sponsors, business partners and other third parties for their use (including for them to directly market to you).  The types of businesses in which such third parties are engaged include but are not limited to the following: NHRA sponsors of various types; magazine publishing and retailing; market analysis and development; participatory databases; non-profit organizations; and advertisers.

If you do not want us to share with third parties your Personal Information for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes, please advise us by emailing us at [**nothirdparties@nhra.com**](mailto:nothirdparties@nhra.com) or writing to us at the address provided in section 17 below.  Please include “Third-Party Marketing Opt-Out” in the subject line of your email or letter. 

**_(b) Third Parties Providing Services on Our Behalf_**.  We may use third party vendors to perform certain services on behalf of the Online Services, such as hosting the Online Services, designing and/or operating the Online Services’ features, tracking analytics, enabling you to purchase tickets and products, and enabling NHRA to send you email newsletters or performing other administrative services.  We may provide these companies with access to user information, including Personal Information, to carry out the services they are performing for you or for NHRA. (For example, online purchases require us to disclose necessary payment information to payment processors. We also may use third parties to send you products or tickets that you purchase, in which case we would provide them with your name, address, and other information to complete your order.)  We do not authorize these vendors to user or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with legal requirements.

**_(c) Co-branded Areas_**. Certain areas of the Online  Services may be provided to you in association with third parties (“Co-Branded Areas”) and may require you to disclose Personal Information in order to register for and access products or services.  Such Co-Branded Areas will identify the third party associates.  If you elect to register for products and/or services at Co-Branded Areas you may be providing your information to both NHRA and the third party associates.  Further, if you sign-in to a Co-Branded Area with a username and password obtained on the Online Services, your Personal Information may be disclosed to the identified third party associates for that Co-Branded Area and will be subject to the posted privacy policies of the relevant third party associates.

**_(d) Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions._**   We may offer sweepstakes, contests, and other promotions (any, a “Promotion”) through the Online Services that may require registration.  By participating in a Promotion, you are agreeing to the terms, conditions and official rules that govern that Promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including, except where prohibited by law, allowing the sponsor(s) of the Promotion to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing associated with the Promotion.  If you choose to enter a Promotion, Personal Information may be disclosed to third parties or the public in connection with the administration of such Promotion, including, without limitation, in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment, and as required by law or permitted by the Promotion’s official rules, such as on a winners list.

(e) **_Administrative and Legal Reasons_**.  We may transfer and disclose your information, including Personal Information, to third parties: (i) in the event we are required to respond to subpoenas or other legal process or if in our good faith opinion such disclosure is required by law; (ii) at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; (iii) to protect and/or defend the Online Services’ Terms of Use or other policies applicable to the Online Services; (iv) to protect the personal safety, rights, property or security of any individual; or (v) to prevent financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual fraudulent or illegal activity.  We may also use IP address or other Device Identifiers to identify users, and may do so in cooperation with copyright owners, internet service providers, wireless service providers or law enforcement agencies in our discretion.  Such disclosures may be carried out without notice to you.

(f) **_Business Transfer._**   NHRA may share Personal Information with its parent and its and their subsidiaries and affiliates.  NHRA also reserves the right to disclose and transfer all information related to the Online Services, including, without limitation, your Personal Information, Demographic Information and Usage Information: (i) to a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of the Online Services or applicable database; or (ii) in connection with a corporate merger, change of control, consolidation, restructuring, the sale of substantially all of NHRA’s assets or other corporate change, including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process.

**5.               What is Online Behavioral Advertising and How Can You Opt-Out?**

We may work with third-party advertising companies who may utilize cookies and web beacons, and data collected on our Online Services, to customize advertisements to you on our Online Services, as well as on other websites or mobile applications in their networks beyond our Online Services. Among other things, these customized advertisements may advertise our products and services on websites or mobile applications not affiliated with us. Some of these ads are online behavioral advertising – which serve advertisements that are more likely to be of interest to you using non-personal behavioral information.  Such ads may contain cookies that allow monitoring of websites and mobile applications (including our own Online Services) and your response to our advertisements.  Cookies or web beacons placed by these companies do not collect Personal Information, and the third-party advertising companies do not have access to or use your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number or other Personal Information; they may however, anonymously track your usage across our Online Services and other website or mobile applications in their networks. We limit companies that place our ads from using information for any purpose other than to assist us in our advertising efforts.

For more information about these third-party advertising companies' privacy policies, visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s website at [http://www.networkadvertising.org](https://www.networkadvertising.org/). If you prefer to not receive targeted advertising, you can opt-out of network advertising programs that use your information. To do so, please visit: the Network Advertising Initiative’s [**opt-out page**](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) **.**

Please note that if you opt out, you will still see advertisements while you are browsing online. However, the advertisements you see will not be based on your preferences or behavior, and thus may be less relevant to you and your interests. Additionally, many network advertising programs allow you to view and manage the interest categories they have compiled from your online browsing activities. These interest categories help determine the types of targeted advertisements you may receive. The NAI Opt-Out Page provides a tool that identifies its member companies that have cookies on your browser and provides links to those companies.

In order for behavioral advertising opt-outs to work on your Device, your browser must be set to accept cookies. If you delete cookies, buy a new Device, access our Online Services from a different device, login under a different screen name, or change web browsers, you will need to opt-out again. If your browser has scripting disabled, you do not need to opt out, as online behavioral advertising technology does not work when scripting is disabled. Please check your browser's security settings to validate whether scripting is active or disabled.

“ _Do Not Track” Functionality._  

At this time, our Online Services do not honor or take actions to respond to Do Not Track signals from browsers because a uniform technological standard has not yet been developed  We continue to review new technologies and may adopt a standard once one is created.  However, many third-party services that collect this type of information permit you to opt out through a separate system. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising from participating third-party providers, as mentioned above, you can visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s website at **[http://www.networkadvertising.org/](https://www.networkadvertising.org/)**  

**6.               Can You Review, Edit or Delete Your Personal Information?**

Yes. You can review, edit or delete Personal Information you have submitted through our Online Services.  (We do not have a mechanism for you to review, edit or delete information we have collected about you through offline activities). 

To review Personal Information you submitted to us through Online Services, we need to verify your identity, so send us a written request by mail to NATIONAL HOT ROD ASSOCIATION, Privacy Policy, 2035 Financial Way, Glendora, CA 91741, asking us to provide a complete copy of the Personal Information you have submitted to us through Online Services.  Tell us whether you want to receive the information by email and if so include your email address, or by regular mail and if so include you mailing address.  You may email your request to [digital@nhra.com](mailto:digital@nhra.com).

To edit or delete any information submitted to us through Online Services, just e-mail us at [ **remove@nhra.com**](mailto:remove@nhra.com) and advise us that you wish us to delete all or a specified portion of your information. Please be sure to give us your name and email address.  NHRA will make good faith efforts to make requested changes in our then active databases as soon as reasonably practicable. 

If you request deletion of your Personal Information, we will make good faith efforts to delete or destroy any Personal Information that we have collected about you through Online Services, solely to the extent permitted by law.  When we delete electronic information that we have collected from or about you, it will be deleted from our active databases but may remain in our archives; for example; there may be residual information that will remain in our archive databases, access logs and other records, which may or may not contain your Personal Information.

**7.               Can You Change Your Permission for Us to Collect, Use or Disclose Personal Information You?**

Yes.  You have several choices.  

(a) **Opt Out of Receiving Marketing Emails from NHRA.   **When you receive promotional emails from us, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving such communications from us and you will have the opportunity to “opt-out” by clicking the “Unsubscribe” link provided at the bottom of an email sent to you by NHRA or by following any other instructions in the applicable email.

However, we may contact you for service-related purposes (such as, but not limited to, notice that we have changed the Online Services or the Privacy Policy) when we believe it necessary or advisable to do so.  You may not opt out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature, but if you do not wish to receive these announcements, you have the option to terminate any account you have with NHRA (or to ask that we delete all your Personal Information, using the procedure in section 6 above). You understand that any such termination of your account may involve deletion of your Personal Information from our live databases.  NHRA will not have any liability to you for any termination of your account or related deletion of your information.

(b)  **Opt Out of Having NHRA Share Your Personal Information to Third Parties for Direct Marketing Purposes**.  As explained in section 4 above, if you do not want us to share with third parties your Personal Information for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes, please advise us by emailing us at [**nothirdparties@nhra.com**](mailto:nothirdparties@nhra.com) or writing to us at the mailing address provided in section 17 below. 

(c)  **Revoke NHRA Permission to Use Your Personal Information.   **To revoke the permission you have given us to use or disclose any Personal Information about you, just e-mail us at our web site at [ **remove@nhra.com**](mailto:remove@nhra.com).

**8.               How Is Your Information Kept Secure?**

We have implemented commercially reasonable measures designed to protect and secure your Personal Information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration and disclosure.  However, no data transmission over the Internet, wireless transmission or electronic storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  Please note that we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you use our Online Services and provide us with your information at your risk.

The safety and security of your information also depends on you.  Where you have chosen a password for any user account, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.  We expect you to not share your password with anyone.

**9.               What About Information Shared via Social Media?**

You may choose to provide your user name for social media (such as Facebook or Twitter) and submit comments to be posted to social media. You have sole control of any information you choose to post publicly.  Your information is never posted publicly unless you initiate, compose, and confirm the sharing activity. Again, we encourage you to read the privacy practices and policies of any third parties before providing information to them. 

10.           What About Information You Disclose Publicly?

**(a) User Generated Content, Social Networking and Public Information _._**   The Online Services may permit you to submit ideas, photographs, user profiles, writings, music, video, audio recordings, computer graphics, pictures, data, questions, comments, suggestions, communications,  or other content, including Personal Information (collectively, “User Generated Content”).  User Generated Content may be published online or offline in any media or format (currently existing or hereafter developed).  Others may have access to this User Generated Content and may have the ability to share it with third parties across the Internet.  Additionally, you may have the opportunity to engage in social networking or other online activities through the Online Services, such as creating a public profile, sharing User Generated Content, and inviting others to connect with you.  Please think carefully before deciding what information you share, including Personal Information, in connection with your User Generated Content or social networking and other online activities.  Please note that NHRA does not control who will have access to the information that you choose to make public, and cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy or keep it secure.  Notwithstanding anything to the contrary herein, this Privacy Policy does not apply to any information that you disclose publicly, share with others or otherwise upload onto the Online Services.  We are not responsible for the accuracy, use or misuse of any content or information that you disclose or receive through the Online Services.

**(b) Name and Likeness**.  We may also publish your name, voice, likeness and other Personal Information that is part of your User Generated Content, and NHRA may use the content, or any portion of the content, for advertising, marketing, publicity and promotional activities.  For full terms and conditions regarding User Generated Content you submit to the Online Services, please review our Terms of Use.

11.           Links to Other Sites

When you use the Online Services, you could be directed to other sites that are beyond our control.  For example, if you “click” on a banner advertisement, or a link, the “click” takes your browser off our Online Services. These other sites may have information practices that are different from ours.  We have no control over, do not review and are not responsible for the privacy policies of such other websites or other locations. You should consult the other sites' privacy notices because we have no control over these third party sites including what information is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties and how it is used.   For example, these other sites and locations may send their own cookies or other tracking technologies to users, collect user data, or solicit Personal Information. 

In addition, our Online Services may offer services or contain content (e.g., racer registration and other racer matters, contests, sweepstakes, promotions, surveys or other items) that are supplied by a third-party and those third parties may collect usage information and your Device Identifier when web or mobile pages from any Online Services are served to your browser.  For example, this may occur with service or content sponsored by or co-branded with identified third parties. Through these relationships, the third parties may obtain personally identifiable information that visitors voluntarily submit to participate in that activity. NHRA has no control over these third parties' privacy practices, including what information is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties and how it is used, so we encourage you to read their privacy policy before providing information to them.

In addition, we may contract with third parties to provide services such as online order selection and fulfillment services for the products, tickets and other services available through our Online Services.  You acknowledge and agree that you may be leaving our Online Services to select products and tickets, and place your product order.  Such third parties’ websites or mobile applications are subject to such third parties’ policies, and when you are on those websites or mobile applications, those third parties’ privacy policy and not this Privacy Policy govern the collection of information from you.

**12.           Social Media Features and Widgets.  **

Some of our Online Services may include social media plug-ins and features (such as the Facebook “Like” button) and widgets (such as the “Share This” button) or interactive mini-programs that run on our Online Services.  In addition, some of our Online Services may also permit or require you to register or log into your account via a social networking platform such as Login with Facebook. 

These social media features and plug-ins may share with us your username and password for the social media services and other information available about you or collected from you on these social media services, in accordance with the terms and conditions ( _e.g.,_ terms of use and privacy policy) of the company providing them.   In addition, the companies providing these features and plug-ins may be able to collect information about you, including your IP address, your activity on our Online Services, and they may notify your connections on the social networking platform about your use of our Online Services.  These social media services may also set a cookie to enable a feature to function properly, and employ unique identifiers which allow your activity to be monitored across multiple websites and mobile applications for purposes of delivering more targeted advertising to you.

Social media features and widgets are hosted by either a third-party or hosted directly on our Online Services.  Your interactions with these plugs-in and features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them.

13.           Transfer of Information to the United States

The Online Services are operated in the United States and intended for users located in the United States.  If you are located anywhere else outside of the United States, please be aware that information we collect will be transferred to and processed in the United States.  The data protection laws in the United States may differ from those of the country in which you are located, and your Personal Information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in the United States according to laws of the United States.  By using the Online Services or providing us with any information, you consent to this transfer, processing and storage of your information in the United States.

**14.            Your California Privacy Rights**

California’s “Shine the Light” law, California Civil Code § 1798.83, requires certain businesses to respond to requests from California customers (those who have an established business relationship with us) asking about the business’ practices related to disclosing personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes.   Alternately, such businesses may have in place a policy not to disclose personal information of customers to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes if the customer has exercised an option to opt-out of such information-sharing.   We comply with this law in both ways.

First, you may request the following information, which will be provided to you via either a writing or e-mail free or charge:  (1) a list of the categories of personal information disclosed by us for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year; and (2) the name and addresses of all third parties that received personal information from us for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year and if, the nature of the third parties’ business cannot reasonably be determined from the third parties’ name, examples of the products or services marketed, if known to us, sufficient to give you a reasonable indication of the nature of the third parties’ business.  Requests for this information should be sent to the contact information set forth in section 14 below.

Alternatively, as discussed above in section 4, if you wish to opt-out of having your Personal Information shared with third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes, please contact us, by email or letter, using the contact information set forth in section 17 below.

**15.            Will This Privacy Policy Change?**

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time, and will do so by providing notice of such changes on our home page and in our online forms requesting personal information. If we make any material changes in the way we use or disclose information about you, we will notify you by posting it on our Online Services so that it is accessible via a link on the home page of any Websites or via a link or tab on any Mobile Apps (or through any other means as we may reasonably undertake or specify – such as through an email message to you).  Therefore, you should review this Privacy Policy from time to time, and before using any of our Online Services or otherwise giving us your information.  The updated Privacy Policy will be effective upon reasonable notice after posting, or such  later date as may be specified in the updated Privacy Policy. 

**16.            Children Under 13**

Unless specifically stated on a Website or Mobile App (such as in a posted Children’s Privacy Policy), our Websites and Mobile Apps are general audience services and are not intended for children under 13 years of age, and we do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 13 years of age.  If you are under 13 years of age, do not provide Personal Information to NHRA through our Websites and Mobile Apps.  If we discover that a child under the age of 13 has provided us with Personal Information through any of our Websites or Mobile Apps and we do not have parental consent, we promptly delete that child’s information from the Website or Mobile App.  If you believe that NHRA has been provided (through one of our Websites or Mobile Apps) the Personal Information of a child under the age of 13 without parental consent, please notify us immediately using the contact information in section 17 below.

**17.            Contact Us**

If you wish to contact us or have any questions about this Privacy Policy or about how Personal Information is used, you can contact us by e-mail at [digital@nhra.com](mailto:digital@nhra.com), or by regular U.S. mail to:

NATIONAL HOT ROD ASSOCIATION

ATTN:  Privacy Policy  
2035 Financial Way  
Glendora, CA 91741

If you are opting out of having your Personal Information shared with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, please include “Third-Party Marketing Opt-Out” in the subject line of your email or letter.
